worksnaps.net 2019-06-12

# Worksnaps - Provacy Policy

Last Updated: May 24, 2018

#### Overview

Worksnaps.net is firmly committed to the privacy of its users. Worksnaps.net adheres to the following principles to protect your privacy: 

  * Worksnaps.net does not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to third parties.
  * Worksnaps.net does not share your contact information with other users or third parties without your consent.
  * Any personally identifiable information that you provide to Worksnaps.net will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.
  * Any information automatically collected by Worksnaps Client program will be secured with industry standard security and will not be shared to anyone other than the users in the system that have been granted such permission.

#### Information Collection

##### Information gathered on our web site

Worksnaps.net is an online Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) provider that provides a verifiable time tracking service to individual users, small businesses and corporations. We collect data from two entry points: the web site and Worksnaps client program (Windows, MAC and Linux). 

We collect the following information during the registration and user profile creation on our web site: 

  * Name
  * Email Address
  * Username (i.e., Login)
  * Password
  * Timezone
  * Portrait (optional)

We use personal information in the file we maintain about you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the site, to provide to you the services offered by the site, resolve service and billing disputes, troubleshoot problems, bill any amounts due from you, customize your experience, detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity. We occationally use email address or other contact information to contact our users to ask them for their input on our services or performing a pre-release testing of certain product features. 

We try to collect minimum user information that is sufficient for us to provide the service to our users. 

We do not rent or sell your personal information nor we send it to any third parties without your consent. 

Worksnaps.net records IP addresses for system administration purposes. This information is used to diagnose server problems, monitor traffic patterns, administer the website, track user patterns, and identify the most popular areas of the website to deliver content most relevant to registered members. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information and are only used to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, except in the case of fraud. 

##### Information gathered by Worksnaps software program

Worksnaps.net is a system that allows a work team to track time and share information for the purpose of productivity and accurate time tracking. The users who wish to track their time have a software program ("Worksnaps Client") running on their computer systems. Worsknaps Client automatically collects the following activity while a user is using the program: 

  * Random screenshot of the computer screen(s)
  * The volume of the keyboard strokes and mouse clicks. (Worksnaps Client only records the volume, i.e., number of clicks each minute. It does not record specific key strokes.)
  * The title of the active window and its corresponding executable program path. This information is recorded with a sampling mechanism, once per minute.
  * Web-cam shot (if enabled)
  * Operation System type and version
  * IP address of the user's computer system
  * Timestamps of the user's computer system

These information is only available to the user himself and any other users in the system that has the permissions to view them. The permissions are provisioned before Worksnaps Client is deployed and used. 

Worksnaps.net does not share the recorded information with any user on the system who does not have the permission to view them, nor share it with any party outside of the company. 

Worksnaps.net may use recorded information for statistical analysis and to maintain the security of the Worksnaps.net platform. 

##### Payment Information

We do not directly collect or store users' payment information, such as credit card number, billing address, or other financial account information. We use third-party payment services, namely, [PayPal](http://www.paypal.com/) and [Wave](http://www.waveapps.com/), to process payments for the subscription of the service. The payment transactions take place completely on the third-party sites and are governed by the security and privacy policy of the third-party services. 

#### Security

We use commercially reasonable methods to keep personally identifiable information securely in our database and file systems. For security of transactions, we use the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts any information you send to us electronically. The encryption process protects your information, by scrambling it before it is sent to us from your computer. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. 

#### Data Retention

We may retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements; this retention period may extend past the point at which you close your account. If you no longer want us to use your personal information or to provide you with the services, you can request that we erase your personal information and close your account. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information we will retain information from deleted accounts as necessary for our legitimate business interests, to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the terms of service and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

If you close your account or cancel the service, the data automatically collected data by Worksnaps client program (see above section "Information gathered by Worksnaps software program"), will be kept for 45 days to give customers the ability to access the history if requested. After 45 days, the data will be backed up and stored in backup vault. A customer can request us to permanently delete the data by sending such request to support@worksnaps.net. 

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are required to use the Worksnaps.net service in full. We use cookies to record current session information, but do not require permanent cookies. 

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. We may use “session ID cookies” to enable certain features of the service, to better understand how you interact with the service and to monitor aggregate usage and work flow on the service. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. To do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “Help”, “Tools” or “Edit” settings). If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all aspects of the service. 

We do not use any cookies for web advertising purpose. 

#### Questions

It is our goal to make our privacy practices easy to understand. If you have questions, concerns or if you would like more detailed information, please email us at info@worksnaps.net.
